canvaslms.com 2018-06-28

# Privacy Policy| Learning Management Software | Canvas

Last Updated: November 17, 2017

Instructure, Inc. ( **“INSTRUCTURE”** ) is committed to protecting your privacy. We have prepared this Privacy Policy to describe our practices regarding the personal information that may be collected from users of our websites which post this Privacy Policy, including http://canvas.instructure.com ( **“SITE”** ), Instructure’s Canvas iOS, Android, and other mobile applications ( **“APPS”** ), and other related educational services ( **“SERVICES”** ). By submitting personal information through our Site, Apps, or Services, you expressly consent to the processing of your personal information in the U.S. in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The use of personal information collected through our service shall be limited to the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

**IMPORTANT NOTICE FOR SCHOOL USERS:** If you are a user (or a parent of a user) who was given access to the Services by the organization you are affiliated with, this Privacy Policy does not govern your organization’s collection, use, or disclosure of personal information through the Site, Apps, or Service. We are not responsible for your organization’s collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information. Please contact your organization to better understand your organization’s privacy practices. Instructure will retain personal information we process on behalf of organizations for as long as needed to provide services and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Instructure uses only de-identified and aggregated data for its own purposes.

IMPORTANT NOTICE REGARDING CHILDREN UNDER 13: This Privacy Policy generally applies to the users of our Services. If however, a user identifies themselves as under the age of 13 (a **“CHILD”** ), we will collect, use and share the Child’s information as described in the subsection below entitled “A Special Note About Children”.

**FOR EU and EEA Residents**

Instructure complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union (“EU”) and Switzerland to the United States (“U.S.”) respectively, as that term is defined in the Privacy Shield Framework. Instructure has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. Instructure is committed to subjecting all personal data received from the EU and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

Instructure’s privacy policy, as provided below, describes the types of personal information that Instructure collects, the types of third parties to which it discloses personal data, and the purposes for which it does so. Instructure collects contact and demographic information to respond to requests or to personalize and deliver the services. Instructure transfers this information to third parties acting as an agent on its behalf. Instructure is accountable for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party. Instructure complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

Residents of the EU and Switzerland have the right to access the personal information that Instructure maintains, and in some cases, may have the right to correct or amend information that is inaccurate or has been processed in violation of the Privacy Shield Principles, to the extent allowed by law. To exercise this right, contact us at privacy@instructure.com. To learn more about the choices you have over your personal information, please see the subsection below entitled, “Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information.”

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Instructure is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Instructure may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Residents of the EU and Switzerland with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy should first contact Instructure at:

6330 S 3000 E, STE 700  
Salt Lake City, UT 84121  
(801) 869.5000

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield [website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Data You Provide to Us.**

We collect information from you, such as first and last name, gender, e-mail and mailing addresses, professional title, company name, and password when you create an account to log in to our network. We also may retain information on your behalf, such as files and messages that you store using your account. If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail, we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail. When you participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information. We also collect other types of personal information and demographic information that you provide to us voluntarily.

**Data Collected via Technology.**

To make our Site, Apps, and Services more useful to you, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) collect information from you, including browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet, which may vary from session to session), domain name, unique device identifiers, information about how you use our Site and Apps, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit. We also use cookies and web beacons (as described below) and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the solutions and information for which you searched and which you viewed. Like most Internet services, we automatically gather this data and store it in log files each time you visit our Site, use our Apps, or access your account on our network. We may link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

**“COOKIES”** are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a website. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our Site.

**“WEB BEACONS”** are digital images we use to log information on our Site and in our emails. We use web beacons to manage cookies, count visits, and to learn what marketing works and what does not. We also use web beacons to tell if you open or act on our emails.

**“FLASH COOKIES”** are used to store your preferences such as volume control or to display content based upon what you view on our websites to personalize your visit. Third party partners who provide certain features on our websites, such as videos, may place Flash cookies on your device. They may use Flash cookies to track your web browsing activity and to display personalized advertising. Flash cookies are different from other cookies because of the amount of, type of, and way in which data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser usually will not remove Flash cookies. To learn more about Flash cookies, who has placed Flash cookies on your device, and how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>. We do not control the privacy practices of the third parties who place or track Flash cookies and this privacy policy does not cover their practices. You should visit the privacy policies of companies who place Flash cookies to understand their practices.

**ANALYTICS.** We use analytics services to help analyze how users use the Site and Apps. These services use cookies and scripts to collect and store information such as how users interact with our Apps, errors users encounter when using our apps, device identifiers, how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve our Site, our Apps, and our Services. Please see the following links for more information about Google Analytics: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>, <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>, and <http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html>.

**Forums**

Our Site and Apps offer community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

**Use of Your Data**

Personal information you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. Instructure uses your personal information in the following ways: to create and maintain your account; to identify you as a user in our system; to operate, maintain, and improve our Site, Apps, and Services; to personalize and improve your experience; to send you administrative e-mail; to respond to your comments or inquiries; to send you surveys, promotional communications about our products and services with your permission; to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity; and to make telephone calls to you, from time to time, as a part of secondary fraud protection or to solicit your feedback with your permission.

**Disclosure of Your Personal Information**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described as follows or with your express consent.

**AFFILIATES.** Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, **“AFFILIATES”** ), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your information with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

**THIRD PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS.** We may share your personal information with third party service providers for the sole purpose of providing you with the Services that we offer you through our Site ( **“INTERNAL PURPOSES”** ). For example, we may share data with service providers who host our websites or provide email services on our behalf.

**OTHER DISCLOSURES.** Instructure may disclose information about you if it believes such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process; or (b) protect or defend the rights, safety, or property of Instructure, users of the Services, or any person including to enforce our agreements, policies, and terms of use, or (c) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of any person (collectively, “a”, “b” and “c”, ENFORCEMENT PURPOSES”).

We may also share de-identified and aggregated data with others for their own uses.

**Social Networking Platforms.**

We may allow you to connect and share information with certain social networking platforms ( **“SOCIAL NETWORKING PLATFORMS”** ) (e.g., a Facebook application). By choosing to use these Social Networking Platforms, you allow Instructure to share information with the Social Networking Platform. For example, you might use an application to publish Instructure related notices on your Facebook wall. If you do not want us to continue to provide your information to the Social Networking Platform, you may change your privacy settings in the Social Networking Platform.

You can also access certain features of our Site using Social Networking Platforms. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name, email address, and other personal information to pre-populate an application.

We do not control the privacy practices of the Social Networking Platforms and sign-in services you choose to use and this privacy policy does not cover their practices, you should visit the privacy policies of any Social Networking Platform or sign-in service you choose to use to understand their practices.

**Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information**

**CHOICES.** We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your personal information. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in e-mails you receive from us or by contacting us directly at the contact information below. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can typically remove and reject cookies from our Site with your browser settings. If you remove or reject our cookies, it will affect how our Site and Services work for you.

When you visit the Site, we and others give you the following choices about use of mechanisms for tracking, including tracking of your online activities over time and across different websites and online services by third parties:

  * Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can typically remove and reject cookies from our Site with your browser settings. If you remove or reject our cookies, it will affect how our Site and Services work for you.
  * You may also render some web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, certain features of the Sites and Services that placed the cookie may not function properly or at all as a result.
  * If you do not wish for us to track emails we send you, some email services allow you to adjust your display to turn off HTML or disable download of images which should effectively disable our email tracking, or you may unsubscribe from our marketing emails as described above.
  * You may opt out of tracking of certain information collected by Google Analytics, one of our analytics providers as discussed above, on the Sites by [clicking here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

While we and others give you the choices described in this Privacy Policy, there are many ways web browser signals and other similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of or honor every mechanism.

**CHANGES TO PERSONAL INFORMATION.** You may change some of your personal information in your account by editing your profile within the Service. You may also request changes or deletions by e-mailing us at the e-mail address set forth below. We will respond to your request, when permitted by law, within 30 days. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may be unable to delete information that resides in our archives.

**SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.** Instructure takes reasonable steps to help protect your personal information in an effort to prevent unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Despite these measures, you should know that Instructure cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Any content you post while using the Services is at your own risk. If you have any questions about security on our Site or Apps, you can contact us at the contact information set forth below.

**A Special Note About Children**

**NOTE TO PARENTS.** We are required under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), with limited exceptions, to obtain verifiable parental consent in order to collect, use or disclose personal information from Children. COPPA allows the Child’s school, school districts and other educational institutions (collectively, **“SCHOOLS”** ) to obtain consent for the online collection of personal information from Children who are students of the School.

If a Child wants to use our Service, he/she must first obtain an account for our Services from the School ( **“Account”** ). Before an Account is provided to a School, we require that the School (on behalf of the Child’s parent or legal guardian ( **“PARENT”)** (a) to consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information of the Child, through the Service, in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and (b) agree that the Child’s online activities are subject to our terms of service.

As required under COPPA, we allow Parents to make certain choices regarding the personal information submitted by their Children as described in this subsection. Parents should make any permitted requests with the School and have the School, as the Parent’s agent, pass on those requests to us. We may rely on the instructions that we receive from the School that we reasonably believe are given by a Child’s Parent to the School. For example, if a representative of the Child’s School contacts us and provides the Account information we request, we may assume that the person calling is acting on behalf of the Child’s Parent.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT, USE AND SHARE:** In general, we collect the same information from Children that collect from other users of the Services, and use and share such information for the same purposes. In addition, our Service also allows Schools to access and interact with their students and their Parents. If your Child’s School creates an Account for your Child, the School may share your Child’s personal information, such as your Child’s grades, test scores, attendance levels, and other information, with us. We may add all of this information to the information we have already collected from your Child via the Service, and we may use it as described in this Privacy Policy. We also may share your Child’s personal information: (a) with the Child’s Parent’s Consent, or with your Child’s School or those directed by your Child’s School We are not responsible for any errors in information your Child’s School provides to us.

**PARENT’S CHOICES REGARDING INFORMATION:** In general, we offer Parents the same choices that we generally offer to other users with respect to the collection, use, retention and disclosure of their Child’s information. In addition, a Parent has the right to review the Child’s personal information, which the Parent may obtain by contacting the Child’s School. After review the Child’s personal information, the Parent may ask us to update or delete the Child’s personal information by requesting such changes through the Child’s School. A Parent may prohibit us from sharing a Child’s personal information with a third party by requesting such prohibition through the Child’s School. Notwithstanding any such requests, we may continue to share a Child’s personal information for Internal Purposes and Enforcement Purposes.

If a Parent chooses to prohibit any future collection, use or disclosure of the Child’s personal information, the Parent may do so by terminating the Child’s Account through the School, and requesting the deletion of the Child’s personal information through the School. Upon receiving such request from the Child’s School, we will delete the Child’s Account information from our live databases and all information and data stored for such Account. Instructure will not have any liability whatsoever for any termination of the Account or related deletion of the Child’s personal information. When we delete personal information, it will be deleted from our active databases but may remain in our archives.

**Contact Information**

Instructure welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [privacy@instructure.com](mailto:privacy@instructure.com) or contact us at the following address or phone number:

Instructure, Inc.  
6330 S 3000 E, STE 700  
Salt Lake City, UT 84121  
(801) 869.5000 

**Changes to This Privacy Policy.**

Instructure may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the "Last Updated" date above. If such changes are material, a notice of the changes will be posted along with the revised Privacy Policy, prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to visit this page from time to time for the latest on our privacy practices.

© 2018 Instructure. All rights reserved.
